Dominic Chalcraft

40 Dyke Road Basement Flat

Basement Flat Mobile: 07393 507 018
Brighton Email: dmshelleytaylor@googlemail.com

East Sussex, BN1 3JB

Personal Statement

My developer experience so far has encompassed many aspects of website design, creation, hosting and maintenance which has allowed me to become a full stack engineer. For the last year I've been focused on back end development, with a heavy emphasis on API and CMS development, along with some amount of sysadmin and devops. Ideally I would like to continue expanding my knowledge into new areas and improve upon the skills I have learned.

Key Skills

Ruby Rails, HAML, ERB Fortran, C MySQL NoSQL (MongoDB, Redis) API's and CMS's TDD and BDD CI, Ansible

Experienced With

Docker Javascript, React AWS (SQS, SES, S3, QS) Rackspace, Server Management Data Analysis Windows, OSX, Linux Ubuntu Server, cmd line Nginx, Passenger

Recent Employment

Developer [May 2019 to Present]

Audioboom PLC

At Audioboom I've mainly been a backend engineer and occasional sysadmin. The tech stack is Rails (MySQL, Redis) with React and I've worked in all parts. During my tenure I've tried to move the focus to a service oriented design in the hope of breaking out some parts of the codebase into their own applications. Some of the main acheivements while working there have been:

- Migrating our email services from an old MX server over to Amazon SES, utilising SQS and setting up our own services for handling of bounces and complaints.
- Migrating our main servers from Solaris to Ubuntu
- Enforcing GDPR and PECR cookie policies across the site (including externally embeded videos)
- General bugfixing and strategic development to refactor and update code

Dominic Chalcraft 2

Developer [October 2015 to May 2019]

Homeflow Ltd

My duties at Homeflow ranged from back end development of our customer facing applications to front end development of our websites as well day to day bug fixes and customer support. I aslo helped manage many of our server deploys in a sysadmin type role, overseeing the architectural improvements required for a rapidly growing business. I often had to design custom solutions to requested client development, taking customer specifications and creating software from the bottom up. Some of the projects I headed were:

- Creating a web portal for clients to view their daily form submissions. This included statistics generation and sorting by various fields as well as the option to safely download the data for their own internal reporting.
- Building a CMS application, using Ruby on Rails, from the ground up. The CMS linked up to the MySQL database via a Rails API which I was heavily involved in creating and maintaining.
- Upgrade of our main API from Rails 4 to Rails 5 and Ruby 2.5 (from 2.1.3).
- An application that allows clients to graphically view their websites main metrics (users, sessions, bounce rates etc) as provided by Google analytics and our own internal data collection.

Education

Physics, MPhil [2012-2013] University of Bath, Claverton Down, BA2 7AY

Theoretical Physics, MPhys (First) [2007-2011] *University of Sussex, Falmer, Brighton, BN1 9RH*

A-Levels [2003-2005]: Physics (A), Chemistry (A), Mathematics (A), Biology (A). *City College Brighton and Hove, Pelham Street, Brighton, BN1 4FA*

G.C.S.E.'s [2002-2003]: Double-Science (A^*A^*) , Mathematics (A), Astronomy (A), English (A). *City College Brighton and Hove, Pelham Street, Brighton, BN1 4FA*

Hobbies

Gaming is something I've enjoyed since I was a child. These days I rarely get a chance to play, but when I do it tends to be grand strategy games or an RPG like the Witcher 3. In the summer I like to get out and about into nature and go hiking. A few years ago I climbed Snowdon, although normally I just head onto the South Downs for a stroll and a few pints/lunch in a country pub after ten to twenty miles. Writing is my truest hobby and certainly something I try to do as often as I can.